<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Evren Ispiroglu</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Evren Ispiroglu</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 23:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Conway&#39;s Law: The Organizational Mirror</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/conways-law-the-organizational-mirror/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 23:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/conways-law-the-organizational-mirror/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We; humans, have been communicating since we stared living together. Firstly, maybe we were just communicating with each other about where to hunt, where to find food etc&amp;hellip; But we evolve over time, and the reason why we communicate is changed. We started to communicate for more complex reasons like find out how to live together, building relationships, expressing emotions, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;sharing knowledge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and so on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As we navigate the complexities of modern work, have you ever stopped to consider how our organizational structures might be influencing the very systems we&amp;rsquo;re trying to build? We started to work with high number of co-workers in our jobs. With a simple math, if there is 100x work to do, we may hire 100 people to do that job correctly. We may think this will fasten the process. But it&amp;rsquo;s not like that. Just as our earliest human ancestors likely communicated effectively around the campfire, so too do our teams and departments today rely on effective communication to get things done. Even we are using all kind of tools for communication and have a great communication between us, the ending result of the job may not be the one we wanted. That&amp;rsquo;s why &lt;strong&gt;John Conway&lt;/strong&gt;, an American computer scientist, came up with the Conway&amp;rsquo;s law. But what happens when these communication structures become outdated or mismatched with the systems they&amp;rsquo;re supposed to support? In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore Conway&amp;rsquo;s Law, a powerful principle that reveals the complex relationship between organizational design and system architecture. Join me as we examine how understanding this law can help us build better systems and stronger teams.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mid-level backend developer with 3+ years of professional experience in distributed systems and high-load microservices. Primary stack: Go (Golang) and Kotlin/Java (JVM). I design event-driven services with Kafka, gRPC, CQRS, and CDC; apply idempotency, backpressure/circuit breaking, and robust observability (Grafana, OpenTelemetry). I operate mainly on on-prem Kubernetes with CI/CD; data stores include PostgreSQL, ElasticSearch, and Couchbase. Motivated by high-load systems and impactful engineering; open to remote/hybrid and relocation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;experience&#34;&gt;Experience&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;trendyol--mid-level-software-engineer-promoted-from-associate&#34;&gt;Trendyol — Mid-level Software Engineer (promoted from Associate)&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nov 2023 — Present • Istanbul, Türkiye&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
